Now we are attracting professional athletes from the
NBA, the NFL, Major League Baseball, and NHL,
and that is the key to marketing.
Welcome back to another video
with the School of Hard Knocks.
I'm here with serial entrepreneur Chris Meroff,
and today we're going to be talking about how
you can start and scale your business in 2023.
Chris, we're so happy to be here with you today.
I want to first start off by asking you,
how many businesses do you currently own right now?
I think in total about 12.
What was the first business that you ever started?
So the first business I ever started
was with my parents back in 1996.
I was 22, and I just
sold that business two weeks ago.
We were focused on consulting for public schools,
so we would bring dollars back to help
pay for services for students with special needs.
Through all the businesses that you've
opened up and investments that you've had,
what was the best financial decision
that you've ever made throughout your lifetime?
That was easily my consulting business that I just exited.
It was a scenario by which
I could have played it safe
in an environment that was really focused on
kind of a lifestyle business that my parents had started,
but they offered me kind of an opportunity
to jump out into another state on my own
and to see what I could do.
I decided to make the leap, move to
an area of the country I knew nobody,
had no resources, knew I was going to
lose a lot of money that first year,
but I believed so much in the
product and the service that we were offering
in a much larger market, and again, I
just am so thankful I made that jump.
Can you give me an
example of two or three businesses
that maybe you'd like to talk about a lot?
A little bit of the origin
story of how you started that,
what did you need to
be able to start that business?
First one is ROI physical therapy.
So it's a great story
for me because several years ago,
I played a two-hour tournament with my nephews,
and I wasn't about to
let them win, so I cheated.
And when I did, I completely destroyed my knee.
Yeah, tore my ACL, MCL,
fractured my patella, tore my meniscus.
And so it went through the
system when I got back to Texas,
and you are just a number.
And so I wanted to solve that problem.
And so I went out, I
recruited a bunch of physical therapists
to join me in a
quest to treat the whole athlete
and not just what's broken, but psychologically, nutrition.
We do a massage therapy.
We do everything that we can for them.
And so that, again, gave the physical therapists
something bigger to shoot for.
They weren't part of this machine.
And I think my excitement for what we were doing
and drawing them in allowed us to really take off.
And now we have a 7,000
square foot facility and a sports arena
that we operate this physical therapy clinic in.
And now we are attracting
professional athletes from the NBA,
the NFL, and the NBA.
NFL, Major League Baseball, and NHL.
Failure is something that a lot of successful entrepreneurs
emphasize as something that it's going to happen
and you have to get comfortable with failing.
And as someone who's had
a ton of success in business,
I'm sure that there's also been some mistakes
that you've made along the way.
What would you say was the worst financial decision
that you ever made?
Wow, that's a great question.
I would say that, yeah, failure, first of all,
is a part of the game.
You just know going in,
you're going to throw money at bad ideas.
I would say my greatest failure
is still really throwing good money after bad.
So I had an investment I made back in 2019.
Didn't pan out.
In fact, the pandemic hit.
We had to shut it down.
We came out of the pandemic and I'm like,
I'm going to resurrect that thing
because I don't want to lose all this money.
Terrible idea.
Lost so much more money.
If I had just buried it back in 2020,
I would have maybe lost a million dollars.
Bringing it back, it cost me another million
only to find out it was a terrible idea.
So how do you really know
if something is a good idea
and that it can pan out and scale
into a really successful business?
It is always down to sales.
I've had so many entrepreneurs come to me
with their idea and they pitch it
and they're like,
we're going to sell millions of these things.
And so I go back to,
well, have you sold any?
And in fact, how many,
if you brought this to a thousand people,
how many of those thousand people thought
that your idea was as good
as you think your idea is?
So sales are your only indicator
on whether you've got a great idea.
Once you get those sales now,
it's about pouring gasoline on more sales.
I'd like to get to at least a thousand conversations
to where it's more than just a pitch
in order for me to understand,
hey, this thing is a good idea
or a bad idea.
Now, a thousand conversations seems like way too many,
but the reality is within six months,
when you break it down, it's not that bad.
So right now we're outside of Coffee and Crisp.
This is one of Chris's brands.
It's a coffee brand.
Curious, what was the inspiration to start it?
I love coffee.
I love community.
And I wanted to create a place
that people would gather
and enjoy the thing that I enjoy the most.
In fact, we can go
check it out if you want.
Let's do it.
Is this a business you knew
that you always wanted to start?
Yes, it's always been high on my list.
I love when people can all come together
and experience,
at least for the most part,
what everybody loves,
a good cup of coffee.
Yeah.
You love coffee,
plus someone who's looking to start a business.
And maybe you have no prior experience
of working within this business.
How did you go about finding out
how can I actually get started within this?
Yeah, any industry that I've entered in
has been the same thing.
I really try to find an expert in that field.
Somebody who's incredibly passionate
about the products and services themselves.
I can provide the passion around business.
They can provide the passion
around what we're actually producing.
And so it's really finding those people,
that enables me to start these kinds of businesses.
I look for those passionate human beings.
And that's how I've gotten myself
from coffee shops to a record label.
It's just finding incredibly passionate people.
When you're starting your path on entrepreneurship,
getting a mentor is something that
a lot of people talk about.
It's really helpful for them.
Is that something that you had early on?
And if so, how did
you go about meeting that person
or reaching out to that person?
When I moved here in 2011 to start my business,
it wasn't on my radar to get a mentor.
Call me just super prideful,
but I was like, I can do this.
I had just left.
I left my parents' company.
Within a week, I ran into
who would be my mentor accidentally.
Met him, heard his story, and I'm like,
man, I think this guy knows how to run business.
And so he agreed to be my mentor.
And yeah, it really proved incredibly valuable.
And now I try to surround myself
with as many mentors as I possibly can.
So someone has an idea, they're launching a business.
How do they generate awareness for that?
Maybe if they don't have capital
and they just want to get a proof of concept
that people actually want this.
Networking is everything.
Something I actually learned way too late in the game,
but now I'm dedicated to it.
I am fine doing three to
four days a week and just networking.
It fights against my internal hustle mentality,
but it's invaluable.
Most of getting business going
is all in who you know.
So you really need to be known.
And one of the businesses you own is a restaurant.
How would you go about
getting awareness in that local area
and building like a drive for
people to want to come there?
We go out to everyone around that restaurant.
We have flyers, we go to every apartment complex.
We do everything we can to make sure
that everybody in that general area
is really aware.
With a restaurant, it's very geographically centered.
So you really need to understand
that people don't really travel that far on the daily
to get to a restaurant.
So you kind of take a circumference
around that particular restaurant,
hit every door you can find.
Marketing is one of those scenarios
by which you've got to understand that marketing
is really just to generate sales.
And so if sales are not
where you need them to be,
that means your marketing plan is terrible.
So throw it out, start over.
The goal is to first identify
who needs to hear about it.
And then what you're going to
do is you're going to create
as many spaces as you can, both in print media,
digital media, in-person conversations
to where they can become aware
that they are the perfect or ideal client.
They just don't know it yet.
What was the biggest challenge
that you've ever faced as a business owner?
And what did you implement to overcome that?
Whether most entrepreneurs want to admit it or not,
it's our pride.
And so when you centralize everything,
all the pressure to solve all the problems,
manage all the crisis,
you yourself are the biggest roadblock to success.
And that was my biggest challenge.
I take a lot of pride in
what I do and how I do it.
I also have a God-given ability
to process very fast information.
So for me, it just came naturally
to solve problems on the fly.
But what I figured out
was that then everybody became quiet
and dependent on me solving.
I was the bottleneck.
And so what I've discovered is in order to scale,
I have to shut up and I have to listen
and I have to give permission for other people
to own the solutions to those problems
and not just do it myself.
What was your secret to marketing
throughout your career as a business owner,
regardless of the industry of the business?
Secret to marketing to me is knowing
and staying laser focused on the product
or problem that you're trying to solve.
And so when you define that really, really well,
what we do is we create
a purpose statement for our company.
And that purpose statement is really designed
to define what exactly is the story
that we're trying to tell.
And by the way, that story needs to change
as your market changes.
But if you know that story inside and out,
now you can identify who exactly is the best person
that you need to go and tell that story to.
And that is the key to marketing
is stop worrying about your websites, even content.
Don't worry about any of that
until your story is nailed down
and that story has to be bought in
with everyone else in the organization.
They have to fully buy into that purpose
in order for you to be successful marketing
those products and services that you have.
Thank you, Chris, so much for having us out
to Wilco Workspaces today.
Where can everybody find you at?
They can find us at DCXcommunity.com.
Awesome, and if you enjoyed today's video,
click this video right here to learn the three steps
that you can take to get
everything you want out of life.